<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<<<<<<< HEAD
<Quotes type="These are quotes from Optimus Prime in the Transformers Movies">
=======
<Quotes>
    
>>>>>>> 9a560c4dd6eb9e77c9f8c1e18ea1f2ea6eb1fcf4
    <Transformers_4>Whenever you look to the stars, think of one of them as my soul. Defend this
        family, Autobots, as they have you. Defend all they can be. There are mysteries to the
        universe were never meant to solve, but who we are, and why we are here, are not among them.
        Those answers we carry inside. I, am Optimus Prime, and this message is to my creators:
        Leave planet Earth alone, because I’m coming for you.</Transformers_4>
    <Transformers_3>In any war, there are calms between storms. There will be days where we lose
        faith. Days where allies turn against us. But the day will never come, where we forsake this
        planet and its people.</Transformers_3>
    <Transformers_One>And now we stand here together, as one. Proving we all have the power to
        transform, to become who we were destined to be. To right wrongs, to make our world better,
        because here, freedom and autonomy are the rights of all sentient beings. Here, all are
        truly Auotobots. This message is a warning is a message to all Quintessons. If you dare
        return to Cybertron, the Autobots will be waiting. I will be waiting. I, am Optimus
        Prime.</Transformers_One>
    <Transformers>Were we so different? They’re a young species, they have much to learn. But I’ve
        seen goodness in them. Freedom is the right of all sentient beings. You all know there’s
        only one way to end this war. We must destroy the cube. If all else fails, I will unite it
        with the spark in my chest. A necessary sacrifice to bring peace to this planet. We cannot
        let the humans pay for our mistakes. It’s been an honor serving with you all. Autobots, roll
        out. </Transformers>
     <Transformers_2> Our races united by a history long forgotten and a future we shall face
        together. I am Optimus Prime, and I send this message so that our pasts will always be
        remembered, for in those memories, we live on. </Transformers_2>
    <!-- I added the new quote for the file @ebeshero -->
</Quotes>
