<essay>Freedom Freedom is defined as many things such as the right to act, speak, or think without
    restraint, the absence of subjection from foreign powers, and the state of not being imprisoned.
    While most people believe that freedom is the right of all people there has been many times that
    where their rights have been taking away from them. Striving for freedom has taken a large part
    in history due to certain actions or laws that causes injustice for people. One example of
    fighting for freedom was the fight to end slavery in 19th century America. This was one of the
    biggest fights for freedom in America since the revolutionary war in the last century. In the
    years following that the Irish fought against the British to free themselves from their rule and
    gain their independence. Now in recent times people still fight for freedom in many ways such as
    to keep their rights regardless of their sexuality, and express their opinions without
    hindrance. In the 1800s, slavery was still very prominent in the United States with many
    advocating for its abolishment. The abolitionists were based in the North with them emerging as
    a movement around 1830 after the Missouri Compromise. As the movement began gaining momentum, it
    caused friction between North and the South because of their opposing views on slavery with some
    people getting attacked for possessing anti-slavery literature. They saw slavery as an
    abomination and worked tirelessly to abolish slavery and return the Africans to Africa. While
    most of them were white, some of the most famous abolitionists were black and/or former slaves
    with the most identifiable being Fredrick Douglass. After he escaped slavery, he became an
    active member of the abolitionists where he went to many abolitionist meetings and wrote many
    books about his experiences as a slave. After the Civil War ended the abolitionist movement did
    not officially dissolve until the passage of the fifteenth amendment, with many prominent
    abolitionists turned to women right’s. Many of their ideals and traditions has served as a model
    of NAACP which was formed in 1909. Freedom for people is an hard task, but freedom for an entire
    country is an harder task to accomplish. In 1541 England took over Ireland and had control over
    it for centuries until the Irish Independence War. It had pitted the British and Irish loyalists
    against the Irish nationalists who wanted their freedom from British rule. Many of the Irish
    citizens wanted independence due to how the British treated them and being forced off their own
    land. The nationalists wanted to rid themselves of the British in the pursuit of autonomy though
    peaceful or violent means. In 1919 the Irish Republican Army was created to resist British rule
    which began the Irish Independence War. Both sides used violent and brutal means to quell the
    other attempts in taking over the country. However in 1921, the IRA was becoming short of
    manpower and weapons due to the conflict resulting in them calling a truce. The Anglo-Irish
    treaty was signed in 1921 with Ireland becoming a free country and Northern Ireland being formed
    and apart of the UK. During the woman’s rights movement, they fought for the right to allow
    women to vote, equal education, and work opportunities. While this started in the 19th century
    it gained prominence in the 20th century alongside the civil rights movement due to the
    aftermath of World War II. Women lives changed drastically during the time of the war with them
    having to provide for the family while their husbands were at war. After that women began to
    protest for equality within the workplace. In 1966, an organization for women rights was formed
    called the National Organization for Women where it found a consensus on measures that were
    essential to ensuring women’s equality. It found many success and failures throughout their
    campaign which ultimately lead Congress to pass many laws that provided women opportunities they
    never had before in the last few centuries. By the 1980s women were allowed into the armed
    forces and had programs to prevent violence against women. In the present day, people have
    fought for many of their rights based on their religion, race, gender, and sexuality. In Cuba,
    if a person identified as LGBT they would be imprisoned or thrown into reeducation camps, now
    LGBT is welcomed and accepted by the country. In America, recently they passed a law that allows
    the freedom for same sex couples to marry. It made in milestone achievement in the LGBT
    community. People all around the world have advocated that everyone should be equal in every way
    regardless of whatever they believe in or not. Youth rebellion is worldwide with it rejecting
    the old style socialism their countries have been stuck with them embracing new liberals ideals.
    In today’s world religions are still being discriminated against because of negative tropes
    people associate them with or not liking it out of fear of the unknown. Freedom has been around
    for years and will continue being a big part of society for years to come. Achieving it is a
    great sense of years of hardship and fighting coming to a close for whoever is fighting the
    battle. Without the sense of freedom people would lose the right of knowing that their lives
    could be better. If Frederick Douglass had not escaped enslavement and had a sense of freedom
    the anti-slave movement would not have been as big as it gotten. </essay>
