<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Letter>
    <Para n="1">I received particular joy at seeing, within the smell of the land, an Old Yorkshire man
    of foreseer who had left his son a merchant in <State>New York</State>, to breath his last in his native land;
    far from the continued storms we met &amp; feeble situation he was in from sea sickness I had been
    apprehensive we should have lost him on the passage.</Para>
    <Para n="2">Coasting the Southwest shore of <country>Ireland</country> on
    that 18th in the evening we made <City type="city in Ireland">Cork</City>, where we were (sp. where) becalmed – we met there a ship
    we had seen two days before at a distance, she was an armed vessel of <City>Liverpool</City>, that had been
    at <Island>Barbados</Island>, and was now returning, she had on board the Governor, and suite of a Dutch
    settlement in the <Island_Country>West Indies</Island_Country>, lately taken by the British troops – There is not much appearance
    of verdure yet on shore – or it might in some respect afford a beautiful prospect – but they
    have a disagreeable way of decorating their coasts with <word meaning="gallows">gibbets</word> (sp. jibbets) here and there –
    Is it not surprising, that a people so enlightened, so humane and so polite should have it so
    arranged, that the first object striking the view of the strangers, who approach their shore
    should be an emblem of the severity of their laws and depravity of some of their people.
    <Object type="old communication device">Telegraphs</Object> were also to be seen on every eminence – this is a late invention to communicate
    intelligence of the approach of an enemy or to give orders to the ships of the Navy – they are
    on a line of communica-tion within distinct view of each other – certain figures are put up
    which are repeated from one (p.35) to the other without being understood by any but those from
    whom the orders issue and the commanders of Posts. We there learnt, by the boats which came from
    the shore, that all was as yet tranquil, that they had only heard of the threats of <Person type="Napoleon, former Emperor of France">Bonaparte</Person>
    which it was not likely, he would be able to put in execu-tion.</Para>
    <Para n="3">After night a fair wind
    springing up, we made sail, and next morning, we were abreast of <Location>Wicklow Moun-tains</Location>, the land is
    high and elevated, but we were at too great a distance to distinctly view it – On the 21st we
    sailed along the Welsh Coast and passed <Town type="town in Wales">Holyhead</Town> – here is elevated land &amp; lofty mountains,
    whose tops are covered with snow, which although they do not prepossess you with an idea of the
    fertility of the country, yet the natural Majestic grandeur of the asylum of the descendants of
    ancient <people type="ancestors of modern british people">Britons</people> strikes the mind with veneration at the magnanimity and unfortunate valor of
    their ancestors who preferred breathing the air of freedom on <Location>Rocky Mountains</Location>, to remaining in
    subjection on their native fertile plains, and calls a sigh for their hero the gallant
    <Person type="anicent british chieftian of the Catuvellauni tribe">Caractacus</Person>.</Para> 
    <Para n="4">In the evening a Pilot comes on board and next day we arrive safe in dock here, the
    pleasure we felt on the occasion can not well be imagined by any but those, who have made a long
    sea voyage. <Word meaning="short for although">Altho’</Word> this was Sunday and business lulled at rest, yet sufficient was to be seen to
    give a stranger some conception of the magnitude of the trade carried on at this place – the
    many store houses, the multitude of ships, the inland canals and docks all denote wealth &amp;
    exertion, these last are of two kind wet and dry, the latter are to receive vessels to be
    repaired; the former are for (p.36) ships to unload and load in; they are made by digging spaces
    to such a level as to be of sufficient depth for the vessels that are to enter the gates of
    these docks at which the vessels, and flow of the tide are received, are shut in the ebb tide by
    which means the water is retained that keeps the ships afloat – were it not for these
    constructions the lading and unlading would be performed with great inconvenience at this port
    which is not naturally well calculated, the River being amazing shallow at low water, and its
    entry rendered difficult from a number of sand banks.</Para> 
    <Para n="5">But the approximate situation of this
    place to several manufacturing town renders it the great emporium of commerce to the West – It
    is here that are deposited the stuffs of <city type="city in England">Manchester</city>, the cutlery of <City type ="City in England">Birmingham</City> and the woolen
    cloths of <English_County>Yorkshire</English_County>, as are also the produce of the west for which they are bartered – it is
    considered next to London for importance in trade: that of <Continent>Africa</Continent> however is a branch that is
    carried on here to some extent and is not honorable to the human spe-cies; for it is a barter of
    their fellow creatures – you must not by this imagine, that the slaves are brought here, no, for
    none would be slaves after they had breathed the British air – they are bought in <Country>Africa</Country> for
    coarse clothes, arms spirits &amp; taken to the West Indies and sold for the produce of these
    Islands, which is brought to this place &amp; from it taken to different parts of the country.</Para> 
    <!-- I highlighted more parts from the letter that I didn't really know too much of. -->
</Letter>
